William Ribeiro Ibiapina

Phone: +55 85 9 9997-8531

E-mail: wribiapina@outlook.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/wribiapina/

GitHub: https://github.com/wrilliam

Profile

Full-stack developer with experience in providing solutions aligned to business requirements and technological infrastructure. Skilled in object-oriented programming, relational databases and automated testing. Experience in working harmoniously with different departments. Always willing to learn and improve myself.

Professional Experience

EY

IT Solutions Development Analyst October 2023 – present day

- Implementation of a low-code application for managing health plans.
- Tools: Pega, Windows.

Stefanini

Full-stack Developer April 2022 – May 2023

- Project 1: Test and activity management; bug fix.
- Project 2: Integration of finance and health centers; integration improvements.
- Project 3: Implementation of an application for data from exonerated servers.
- Tools: Visual Studio, GitLab, SQL Server Management Studio, pgAdmin.
- Languages/Frameworks: C#, .NET Core, SQL, HTML5, CSS3, TypeScript, Angular, ASP.NET Core.
- Methodologies: Scrum.
- Databases: SQL Server, PostgreSQL.

Group of Computer Networks, Software Engineering and Systems (GREat)

Full-stack Developer
January 2021 – February 2022

- Web application development and database maintenance.
- Tools: Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, SQL Server Management Studio, GitLab.
- Languages/Frameworks: C#, .NET Core, xUnit, LINQ, SQL, T-SQL, Angular, HTML5, CSS3, TypeScript, jQuery, Bootstrap.
- Methodologies: Scrum.

Ormel

Back-end Developer
July 2020 – December 2020

- ERP development and database maintenance; automated tests.
- Tools: Eclipse, pgAdmin, Bitbucket, Jira, Jenkins, Selenium.
- Languages/Frameworks: Java EE, SQL, PL/SQL, HTML5.
- Databases: PostgreSQL.

Education

Federal University of Ceará

Computer Engineering (halfway) February 2007 – December 2012

- Tools: Dev-C++, CodeBlocks, Eclipse.
- Languages/Frameworks: C, C++, Java EE, Assembly.

Federal University of Ceará

Digital Media and Systems (completed) August 2016 – December 2018

- Tools: Sublime Text, NetBeans, pgAdmin.
- Languages/Frameworks: HTML, CSS, Java SE, C++, SQL.

SENAP

System Development (halted) January 2020 – January 2021

- Tools: Visual Studio, SQL Server Management Studio, Visual Studio Code, Construct
- Languages/Frameworks: Visual Basic, C#, .NET Core, SQL, Angular, HTML5, CSS3, TypeScript, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Ionic.
- Architectures: MVC.

Projects and Self-learning

- **Digital interactive TV programming**: Development in partnership with local broadcasters (February 2013 July 2014).
 - o Tools: Ginga.
 - o Languages: Lua.
- **Musical data management**: Implementation of MIR technologies (January 2017 December 2017).
 - o Publication of a short paper in SMD Magazine.
 - o Tools: Visual Studio Code, pgAdmin.
 - o Languages: SQL, Python.
- **Web development**: Creation of small websites (January 2019 December 2019).
 - o Tools: Visual Studio Code, GitHub.
 - o Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, PHP.
- Game development: Study and creation of game projects (June 2023 August 2023).
 - o Tools: Unity, Visual Studio, GitHub, Eclipse, Visual Studio Code.
 - o Languages: C#, Python, Java SE, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript.
 - o Databases: MySQL.
- **System architecture**: Bootcamp for Pega system architects (August 2023).
 - o Tools: Pega.

Hard Skills

- Agile Methodologies (Scrum)
- Automated and Unit Tests
- Maintenance and Programming for Databases (SQL, PL/SQL, T-SQL)
- Object-Oriented Programming (C#, Java, Python)
- Web Development (HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Angular, ASP.NET Core)
- Development Tools (Visual Studio, Eclipse, GitHub, Jenkins)
- Database Management Systems (MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQL Server)
- Architectures/Protocols (MVC, REST)

Soft Skills

- Effective communication
- Teamwork
- Problem solving
- Time management
- Adaptability